Guide to the South Africa Historical Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Additional Material, Circa 1885-1950; Accession 2011-M-041
  - Maps
    - Proposed Boer "homeland", Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Photographs
    - Mining in Barberton, S.A., Moodie's Corporation, Circa 1885-1890 (Box 1, Folder 4-11)
      Includes mining at Pigg's Peak, Swaziland.
  - Publications
    - Eerste Sendingsinode/Sinodo sa Pele (First Mission Synod), 1910 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      Print of group photograph with advertisement for church publications on back.
    - The Researcher
      - National Reconstruction in South Africa, by George Bosman, no. 2, 1944 September (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - The Cost of Marketing and Distribution of Perishable Produce in South Africa, by George Bosman, no. 3, 1944 December (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - The Springbok: Official Organ of the South African Legion of the B.E.S.L. (British Empire Service League), vol. 33, no. 5, 1950 May (Box 1, Folder 15)
      Special issue on General Smuts.
    - The Workers and the War leaflet, Circa 1900 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Additional Material, 1880-1890; Accession 2014-M-021
  Correspondence of Charles O. Nash, an Englishman, written to his sister Edie, and documenting his experiences working and traveling in South Africa during the gold rush of the late 19th century. The title of each letter in the inventory is indicative of the location from which it was written.
  - Descriptive information from Denning House Antiquarian Books and Manuscripts, Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Caledon Villa, Smithfield, O.F.S., 1880 May 30 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Boundary Cottage, Smithfield, O.F.S., 1880 October 7 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Caledon Villa, Smithfield, O.F.S., 1880 November 4 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Boundary Cottage, Smithfield, O.F.S., 1880 August 23 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Boundary Cottage, Smithfield, O.F.S., 1881 January 9 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Bleomfontein, O.F.S., 1883 April 11 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Zeerust Marico Transvaal, 1884 May 14 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Rockhaven, Smithfield, O.F.S, 1885 June 8 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Rockhaven, Smithfield, O.F.S., 1885 November 24 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Rockhaven, Smithfield, O.F.S., 1886 September 4 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Rockhaven, Smithfield, O.F.S., 1886 July 29 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Johannesburg, South African Republic, 1887 January 15 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Johannesburg Zuid Afrikaansche Republick, 1887 June 18 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Buxley Syndicate Luipaards-vlei P.O. Krugersdorp, 1888 May 28 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Luipaards Vlei Krugersdorp, 1888 November 14 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Hillsleigh Alival North Cape Colony, 1890 July 4 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Letter from Ernest O. Nash, Reefton (New Zealand), 1884 July 17 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Letter and photograph, 1885 December (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Additional material, 1802-1961; Accession 2015-M-001
  - Printed material, 1802-1961 (Box 1, Folder 1)